(
"ai_sub_version": "2.8.0",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 7,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 15,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "gemini-cli:gemini-3-flash-preview",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.1-flash-lite-preview",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"gemini_cli": (
"timeout": 600,
"overwrite_system_prompt": false
),
"ollama_search": (
"key": "**********"
),
"web_search_tool": "ollama",
"validation_buffer_ms": 1000
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": true,
"fps": 1,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": "libx264"
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"run": 3,
"max": 9,
"delay": 30
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false
)
UNCUT ROCK!! feat. LIVE BAND!
MORI CALLIOPE 6TH BIRTHDAY CONCERT
[Title: Uncut Rock!! feat. Live Band!
Mori Calliope 6th Birthday Concert]
MORI CALLIOPE BIRTHDAY LIVE
[Text: Mori Calliope Birthday Live]
01 AZKi
[Text: 01 AZKi]
02 NERISSA RAVENCROFT
[Text: 02 Nerissa Ravencroft]
03 TOKINO SORA
[Text: 03 Tokino Sora]
04 HOSHIMACHI SUISEI
[Text: 04 Hoshimachi Suisei]
05 MORI CALLIOPE
[Text: 05 Mori Calliope]
UNCUT ROCK!! feat. LIVE BAND!
MORI CALLIOPE 6TH BIRTHDAY CONCERT
[Title: Uncut Rock!! feat. Live Band!
Mori Calliope 6th Birthday Concert]
Rivals and Equals
[Song: Rivals and Equals]
Base instincts take control
Like primal ways of a warrior
Is it glory you're after, like me?
Underestimated everywhere I turn
Taking aim but it doesn't make a difference at all
I got a million different enemies I cannot recall
You're rocking up to a battle when you know that you'll fall
Hidden motivation, watch it all burn
I gotta tell you
I never liked you
Now would I lie to you?
Let me ignite you
When thunder crashes down
When the world caves under my pressure
There'll be no one to save
Where is your pride, your human will to survive?
Was it just
Empty words for your grave?
I reach inside this soul
Now all that remains
Is delusion and decay
Cuz of you, I live this way
We're not rivals
We're not equals
You're just confused
Rivals and Equals
[Title: Rivals and Equals]
Lightning never strikes twice in the same spot
So go ahead and run up on me so you get your shot
Best the weapon that you're hiding, come already or not?
Another life and you would never get a second thought
Thinking your pride's different than mine
Taking a fight or so it seems
But we still gotta
Protect all our friends from our enemies
Wouldn't you agree?
Forging fires of hell
God can't betray you
If I'm a fallen angel
What does that make you?
I'm not debasing myself
To see the same view
When it's your pride on the line
No one can save you from mine
We're not rivals!
We're not equals!
皆さん、ハロー！
Hello, everyone!
あ、ありがとう！森カリオペです。
Oh, thank you! I'm Mori Calliope.
森カリオペです！バースデーライブに来てくれて本当にありがとう！
I'm Mori Calliope! Thank you so much for coming to my birthday live!
ハッシュタグはここ、ここ、ここ！#UNCUTROCK です！
The hashtag is right here! It's #UNCUTROCK!
みんな、チェックしてね！
Check it out, everybody!
今日のテーマはもちろん誕生日だよね？私の誕生日です。
Today's theme is obviously birthday, right? It's my birthday.
後ろを見て、石があるよ！なんてこった！
If you look behind us, we've got stones! Oh my god!
どんな石かな？ゲストによって誕生石が変わるのかも？
What kind of stones, I wonder? Maybe birthday stones depending on the guest?
まあ、森カリオペはダイヤモンドだから。
Well, Mori Calliope is diamond.
だから、後ろにはもちろん白が見えるはずだよ。
So, of course, you will see white behind me.
そう！ゲストと一緒にオリジナル曲を歌ったり、自分の曲を歌ったりするんだ。
Yes! The idea is to sing original songs with guests, and also my own songs.
今、コメントを見てるよ。
I'm looking at the comments right now.
画質があまり良くないから、結構ラグがあるね。
The quality isn't very high, so there's a pretty big lag.
でも見てるよ...拍手の絵文字がいっぱいだ！
But I'm looking... Phew, there's a lot of clapping!
なんてこった！本当にその通りだね。
Holy cannoli! Holy cannoli is right.
こんばんは、こんばんは！
Good evening, good evening!
コメント見てます！
I'm looking at the comments!
うわあ、すごい！ハッピーバースデー、ハッピーバースデー！
Wow, amazing! Happy birthday, happy birthday!
お祝いの言葉、ありがとうございます！
Thank you for the happy birthday wishes!
それから、後ろにあるのは石だけじゃないんだ。
And you know what? Behind me is not only stones...
素晴らしいバンドも参加してくれてるよ！
...but I also have a fabulous band joining me!
そう、生バンドだよ！
Yes, that's right! Live band!
来てくれたバンドの皆、本当にありがとう。
Thank you so much to the band for coming.
特に、私たちが本当に尊敬している方が来ているんだ。
In particular, we have somebody that Calliope and I really respect.
今日はパークさんが一緒にいてくれます！
Today Park-san is here with us!
カリちゃん、ハッピーバースデー！
Calli-chan, happy birthday!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
今日はよろしくお願いします！
I'm looking forward to today!
よろしくお願いします！
I'm looking forward to it too!
パークさんは今までで一番好きなベーシストの一人なんだ。
Yeah, Park-san is one of my favorite bass players ever.
私の曲も2曲やってくれたんだ、OrpheusとSepia。
He's done two songs for me, in particular, Orpheus and Sepia.
OrpheusとSepiaのベースを弾いてくれました。
He played the bass for Orpheus and Sepia.
パークさんは本当にリスペクトしてます。はい。
I respect Park-san a lot. Yes.
バンドには他にも素晴らしいメンバーがいるし、ゲストもいるんだ。
But I have so many wonderful members in the band today, and guests as well.
あんまり時間を取らせたくないんだけど...
I don't want to take up too much more time, but...
とにかく、ゲストと一緒に歌い始めないとね。
Anyway, we should probably sing with guests...
皆で練習してきた成果を見せたいから。
...because I want to showcase all that we've been practicing together.
それじゃあ、始めよう！
So, let's go ahead and begin!
最初の...最初のゲスト、おいで！
The first... the first guest, come on!
I can't control myself
[Song: I can't control myself]
閉ざした世界 かすかに聞こえる音
The closed world, the sound I can faintly hear
世界で二人きりみたいだ
Like we're the only two in the world
届きそうな手 すれ違った心が
Reaching hands, hearts that passed each other by
ちょっと 痛むんだ
They hurt a little
ここで待って
Wait here
決められないままで
I can't decide
戸惑い 溢れて しまうよ
and the confusion overflows
もう何度も繰り返した
I've repeated it so many times
零れた想いを 数えて
Counting the spilled feelings
何度も繰り返した
I've repeated it so many times
世界 世界 開くのを待っている
World, world, waiting for it to open
壊れた世界
The broken world
周り続ける針は
The needle keeps spinning
ちぎれた意識
connecting the torn consciousness
繋いでいく
and joining it together
歪んだ金属音
Distorted metallic sound
鳴り響く
it rings out
心にちょっと
it echoes in my heart
響くんだ
a little
ここで待って
Wait here
記憶繋げないまま
Without connecting the memories
記憶繋げないまま...
Without being able to connect my memories...
狂って壊れてしまうよ
I'll go mad and break apart
もう何度も繰り返した
I've already repeated it so many times
神様に願いをかけて
Making a wish to God
何度も繰り返した
I've repeated it so many times
世界 世界 開くのを待っている
Waiting for the world, the world to open
もうなんにも いらないから
Because I don't need anything anymore
零れた想いは幻
The spilled feelings are an illusion
何度も繰り返した
I've repeated it so many times
世界 世界 開くのを...
The world, the world, to open...
もう何度も繰り返した
I've already repeated it so many times
神様に願いをかけて
Making a wish to God
何度も繰り返して
Repeating it so many times
世界 世界 開くのを待っている
Waiting for the world, the world to open
イェーイ！
Yeah!
最初のゲストはAZKi先輩です！
Our first guest is AZKi-senpai!
AZKi！右手にマイク、左手に地図
AZKi! Mic in the right hand, map in the left hand
あなたのハートにゼロゲッサー、カリオペちゃん、ハッピーバースデー！
Zero-guessing your heart, Calliope-chan, Happy Birthday!
ありがとうございます！Birthdayです、誕生日です
Thank you very much! It's my birthday, my birthday
誕生日カル！ありがとうございます
Birthday Call! Thank you very much
え、さっき一緒に歌った曲、大好きです
Yeah, I love the song we just sang together
ありがとうございます。なんと、AZKiのオリジナル曲を一緒に歌わせていただきました
Thank you very much. We actually got to sing AZKi's original song together
そうですよね。ずっとバンドアレンジ聴きたかったから、選びました
That's right. I've always wanted to hear it in a band arrangement, so I chose it
めっちゃ熱かったです！
It was so hot!
やった！楽しかったよね
Yay! It was fun, wasn't it?
バンドの演奏もすごかったです
The band's performance was also amazing
ありがとうございます。イェイ！あ、ちなみに...
Thank you very much. Yay! Oh, by the way...
ステージと見てほしい
I want you to look at the stage
いや、すごい！めちゃくちゃぴかぴか光ってる！
Whoa, incredible! It's shining so brightly!
ぴかぴかストーン！
Shiny stones!
そうだよね。素敵ですよね
That's right. It's lovely, isn't it?
素敵なステージです
It's a lovely stage
ちなみに...
By the way...
AZKi先輩の...
AZKi-senpai's...
誕生石は知ってる？
Do you know your birthstone?
AZKiの誕生石は... ま、7月なんですけど...
AZKi's birthstone is... well, I was born in July...
ルビー！ルビー、この色！
Ruby! Ruby, this color!
そう、なりました！すごい！
Yes, it turned [ruby]! Amazing!
こっち色がかわるんですね今日は
The color changes today, doesn't it?
すごい、めちゃ赤です
Amazing, it's very red
そうですね。きれい
That's right. Beautiful
すごくきれいから、一緒になんか、あの写真撮りたいと思い
It's so beautiful, I'd like to take a photo together
撮りたい、撮りたい！せっかく！
I want to, I want to! Since we're here!
Take screenshots!
Screenshot!
いい感じです！
Looking good!
イェイ！ありがとうございます
Yay! Thank you very much
じゃ、ま、生ライブだからやっぱり水飲みたいと思います
Well, since it's a live show, I really want to drink some water
水は飲もう！
Let's drink water!
水乾杯です！はい、乾杯！
A water toast! Yes, cheers!
Cheers!
Okay, okay. やった！次の曲...
Okay, okay. Yay! The next song...
お、次の曲はなんだろうな？
Oh, what's the next song?
もう一曲ありますよね一緒に
We have one more song together, right?
あります！そう、そうですね。さっきAZKi先輩のオリ曲歌いましたね
We do! Yes, that's right. Earlier we sang AZKi-senpai's original song
今回はカリオペのオリ曲です。歌わせていただきます
This time it's Calliope's original song. We'll be singing it
The next song is Calliope's original, "Future Island"!
未来島 -Future Island-
[Title: Future Island]
危険な海に浮かぶ島エッグヘッド
Dangerous sea, floating island, Egghead
世界変える未来島のラボフェーズ
Changing the world, Future Island's lab phase
最高の頭脳叶えるよ願望
Best brain, wishes will come true
未来のお宝さがしちゃお
Let's search for future treasure
天才が引き起こす発想の奇跡
Genius causes a miracle of ideas
脳内で終わらせない夢のファンタジー
A fantasy of dreams that won't end in the brain
世界がひっくり返るテクノロジー
Technology that turns the world upside down
大体叶えちゃうラボラトリー
A laboratory that grants almost anything
正(シャカ) 悪(リリス) 想(エジソン) 知(ピタゴラス) 暴(アトラス) 欲(ヨーク)
Shaka, Lilith, Edison, Pythagoras, Atlas, York,
6人のサテライト
6 satellites
湧きだすアイディア止まらない
Ideas gushing out, can't stop
忙しすぎて猫の手も借りたい
Too busy, wish for a cat's hand
海も波も超えてゆく海賊王
Exceeding the sea and waves, Pirate King
常識変えてゆく発明王
Changing common sense, Invention King
そんな奴らに憧れてきた
I've been longing for those guys
次は誰が王になる？
Who will be king next?
無限の夢 未来の知恵 ひらめきを巻き起こせエッグヘッド
Infinite dreams, future wisdom, stir up the flash, Egghead
無限の夢 未来の知恵 過去も世界も飛び越して
Infinite dreams, future wisdom, jump over the past and the world
ベガパンク生み出すよアイディア
Vegapunk, producing ideas
ベガパンク ベガパンク...
Vegapunk, Vegapunk...
ベガパンク
Vegapunk
革命をここからベガパンク
Revolution starts here, Vegapunk
ベガパンク
Vegapunk
危険な海に浮かぶ島エッグヘッド
An island floating in a dangerous sea, Egghead
世界変える未来島のラボフェーズ
The future island's lab phase changing the world
This mind is undefeated
Until my goal's completed
Let's keep on searching for the treasure of “to-come”
Genius
天才が引き起こす発想の奇跡
A miracle idea, gotta set it free
Mysterious
脳内で終わらせない夢のファンタジー
Fantastic dreams are burning up inside of me
Deliriously
世界がひっくり返るテクノロジー
Turn the world around with new technology
Here we come
大体叶えちゃうラボラトリー
A laboratory cast upon the sea
Truth fades into Evil
Then to Contents of Mind
Right into Knowledge, Greed and Violence
Six satellites
Ideas can't stop rushing out
Stop thinking they might
Could use a hand or two, I'm busy working into the night
The pirate king who braves the ocean while in search of elysian
A ruler of invention that can modify all reason…
Once watched in jealousy, no someday I've gotta be
Next on the throne, I know what I've got to do
無限の夢未来の知恵
Infinite dreams, future wisdom
ひらめきを巻き起こせエッグヘッド
Stir up inspiration, Egghead
無限の夢未来の知恵
Infinite dreams, future wisdom
過去も世界も飛び越して
Leaping over the past and the world
ベガパンク
Vegapunk
生み出すよアイディア
Generating ideas
ベガパンク
Vegapunk
革命をここからベガパンク
Revolution starts here, Vegapunk
ベガパンク
Vegapunk
Okay, let's go!
言うこと聞かなきゃ振りかざす正義
If you don't listen, I'll brandish justice
世界守る軍団の大義
The cause of the army protecting the world
秘密巡る怪しいたくらみ
A suspicious plot surrounding secrets
過去の記憶に隠された狂気
Madness hidden in memories of the past
真実追う
Chasing the truth
危険な遊戯
A dangerous game
謎に満ちた理想の夢のエネルギー
Ideal dream energy full of mystery
天才が魅せる世界のカタチ
The shape of the world shown by a genius
どこへ向かう未来の島エッグヘッド
Where is the future island Egghead heading?
Thank you Egghead! Bye-bye! See you later!
Dancing Reed
[Title: Dancing Reed]
All right! Everybody welcome to the stage Sora-senpai! Happy Birthday! Yeah!
Okey Dokey 返事はいいけど冗談なら笑えないよ
Okey Dokey, your reply is fine, but if it's a joke, it's not funny
渋滞 曖昧 どっちを向いちゃうの
Congested, ambiguous, which way are you facing?
蜃気楼に手を伸ばした微熱のような夢物語
A dreamlike story like a slight fever, reaching for a mirage
そんな光は見ない振りしていた
I was pretending not to see that light
ざわめく鼓動
A throbbing heartbeat
まだ行かないで
Don't go yet
幻じゃ嫌だよ
I don't want it to be an illusion
私を奪って
Take me away
魅惑のDancing Dancing night
Alluring Dancing Dancing night
拡がって収まんない Universe
An expanding Universe that won't subside
君の表情は 私の森羅万象を書き換えちゃうかも 責任重大ね
Your expression might rewrite my whole world, quite a responsibility
一切合切Dance Dance Dance We Are Dancing Reed
Everything Dance Dance Dance, We Are Dancing Reed
夢中になって絡み合った ゼログラビティ
Entwined and obsessed, zero gravity
構わずDance Dance Dance Just a Dance Just a Dance
Without a care Dance Dance Dance, Just a Dance Just a Dance
声を闇に預けたまま
Leaving our voices in the darkness
目を覚ましても離れないで
Even if I wake up, don't leave me
Woo! Hey! Yeah!
Maybe Needy 正気じゃないのよ
Maybe Needy, I'm not in my right mind
体温が忘れられない
I can't forget the body heat
誰 彼 そんなじゃないから独り占めしてEuphoria
Who or whom, it's not like that, so keep the Euphoria all to yourself
気にしてない様な 言葉は装飾で
Words like I don't care are just decorations
メイクの様には流せない
Can't be washed away like makeup
360°偽りだって隠しきれぬような
Even if it's 360 degrees of lies, it can't be hidden
私に構って 嬉しいなんて
Giving me attention, I'm so happy
Crazy Crazy Love
摩天楼から連れさらって
Take me away from the skyscraper
君の表情は 私の深層心理をすり替えちゃうのよ 責任重大ね
Your expression switches my deep psychology, quite a responsibility
過ぎ去ったネオン残像 Shooting Star
Passing neon afterimage, Shooting Star
All right! 盛り上がってこう!
All right! Let's get hyped!
グライダーみたいに漂えば幸も不幸もなかった
If I drifted like a glider, there was neither happiness nor unhappiness
指先でまた君を探している
Searching for you again with my fingertips
その声を聴かせてよ
Let me hear that voice
[曲：Dancing Reed]
[Song: Dancing Reed]
教えてよ
Tell me
私にかまって
Pay attention to me
教えてよ 恋の先を
Tell me what lies beyond love
広がって 収まらないね
It's spreading and won't subside
君の存在は
Your existence is...
私の将来 持っても
even if it holds my future,
踏み込んだのよ 好き合ってよね
I've stepped in, so let's love each other
Dance dance dance with me tonight
夢中になってご覧よ
Just try getting absorbed in it
After the gravity
Keep on dance dance dance just to dance
Just to dance
声は闇に預けたまま
Leaving our voices in the darkness
目を覚ましても 離れないで
Even when I wake up, don't leave me
Yes! 2人目のゲストは、そら先輩です！
Yes! Our second guest is Sora-senpai!
はーい、みんな！ こんそらーめ、ときのそらです！
カリちゃん、お誕生日おめでとう！
Hi everyone! Kon-Sorame, Tokino Sora here!
Calli-chan, Happy Birthday!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
そら先輩…本当にありがとうございます。
ずっと一緒に歌いたかったから。
Sora-senpai, thank you so much.
I've always wanted to sing with you.
あ、本当ですか？ ありがとう！
Oh, really? Thank you!
嬉しいですよ、マジで。やったー！ ヘイヘイヘイ！
I'm so happy, seriously. We did it! Hey hey hey!
ヘイヘーイ！
Hey hey!
可愛いよね！ すごい…すごい沢山踊りました！
So cute, right? We... we danced so much!
本当だったね！
We really did!
アイドルわぉ！ ドキドキ！
Idol wow! Doki doki!
ドキドキ！
Doki doki!
Yes! あ、見て！ Xでトレンド3位！
日本でトレンド3位です！ 本当にありがとう！
Yes! Oh, look! Trending #3 on X!
Trending #3 in Japan! Thank you so much!
おめでとうー！
Congratulations!
トレンドやったー！
A trend, we did it!
やったー！
We did it!
ありがとう！ 沢山使ってね、プリーズ！ #UNCUTROCK
Thank you! Please use the hashtag! #UNCUTROCK
プリーズ！
Please!
本当にありがとう。あぁ、幸せ。ありがとう。
Thank you so much. Ah, I'm so happy. Thank you.
そして今回、大好きな曲を一緒に歌いました。
「Dancing Reed」！
And this time, we sang a song I love together.
'Dancing Reed'!
「Dancing Reed」！
わぉ、すごいなんかパーティー・ハッピーですよね。
大好きです。
Wow, it's such a happy party song, isn't it?
I love it.
ダンサボー！
Danceable!
めっちゃ良かった！
It was so good!
そしてほら、エメラルド来た！
And look, the Emerald is here!
ね！ 綺麗！ 緑！
Right! It's beautiful! Green!
ですよね。誕生石ですよね。
5月の誕生祭、エメラルドです。
Exactly. It's the birthstone, right?
The May birthstone is Emerald.
Emerald! おぉ、すごい良い発音！ ナイス・イングリッシュ！
Emerald! Wow, great pronunciation! Nice English!
あ、本当？ ありがとう！
Oh, really? Thank you!
Very good. そうですね。ちなみに、写真撮ろうか？
Very good. So, shall we take a photo?
あ、撮ろう！
Oh, let's!
Let's do it!
この写真もアップしてね、X！
Please upload this photo to X too!
よろしくね！
Looking forward to it!
Yes, よろしくね！ わー、楽しい。じゃあ、水飲みましょう。
Yes, please! Wow, this is fun. Now, let's drink some water.
あ、お水！
Ah, water!
乾杯！
Cheers!
飲んだほうが良いですよね。
It's better to drink, right?
そうね。水は大事。
Yes. Water is important.
そうだよ。楽しいなー、生ライブ！
That's right. Live shows are so fun!
楽しいね！
They are!
もう一曲一緒に歌いたいんですけど、大丈夫ですか？
I want to sing one more song with you. Is that okay?
もちろん！
Of course!
Let's do it! オッケー！
皆さん、次の曲を聴いてください。
Let's do it! Okay!
Everyone, please listen to this next song.
この曲を選んだ理由は分かってもらえるはずです。
そら先輩がこの曲のPVに出演しているからです。
You'll understand why I chose it.
It's because Sora-senpai is in the PV for this song.
私のオリジナル曲「Dawn Blue」を楽しんでください！
Please enjoy my original song, 'Dawn Blue'!
つかまえて、ほら この shooting star
Catch it, look, this shooting star
A world of our fiction awaits...
ずっと同じ毎日に迷いがあっても
Even if there's hesitation in the same daily routine,
気づかないふりをしていたんだ
I was pretending not to notice.
ほんのちょっとの勇気がまだ出せなくって
Because I couldn't find just a little bit of courage yet,
まどろむ宇宙で彷徨っていた
I was wandering in a slumbering universe.
夜空に浮かぶ
Floating in the night sky,
星に願いをかけるんだ
I'll make a wish on a star.
I hope...
抱いてる夢を
The dream I hold...
絶対諦めたくない
I never want to give up on it.
走りだすから
Because I'm starting to run.
追いかけて今 あの shooting star
Chase it now, that shooting star.
見たことのないストーリー進んでいくんだ
A story never seen before is moving forward.
いつの日にかきっと
Surely someday,
描いたセカイへ 辿り着けるように
So that we can reach the world we envisioned.
Let go...
Of the days you thought mattered so, life goes on, tomorrow's rolling in
...the dream we sought so long?
もっと誰でもない自分になりたいんだ
I want to be myself, no one else
新しい風が心を揺らした
A new wind shook my heart
It takes something to believe
The wish we were promised could really come to life
And so,
If this is how the story goes
To find that strength inside, I'll remember why back then
You took my hand, and you said...
つかまえて、ほら この shooting star
Catch it, look, this shooting star
さあ、まずは一歩 踏み出して 恐れずにゆこう
Come on, first take one step, step out and go without fear
いつの日にかきっとまだ見ぬ世界へ
So that one day I can surely reach the world I haven't seen yet
辿り着けるように
So that I can arrive there
夜明けに咲いた月が
The moon that bloomed at dawn
眩い ブルーの 空に溶けてく
melts into the dazzling blue sky
You and I, an undecided future,
Doesn't matter if the final truth hurts
もうすぐ 朝が 動き出すから
Because the morning will move soon
抱きしめて今 この shooting star
Hold it tight now, this shooting star
見たことのないストーリー
An unseen story
I'll be here betting on that
Fearsome heart
Cuz you're that shooting star
It's hopeless now, but maybe if you take that step
Into the darkness, you'll find me
Running by your side until the dawn
In the end, it's you and me
Us against tomorrow
Face the world that we had dreamed
Dry your eyes, and don't look back.
Thank you so much Sora-senpai!
また一緒に歌いましょう！
Let's sing together again!
おめでとう、カリちゃん！
Congratulations, Calli-chan!
Thank you! Bye bye!
またねー！
See you!
Bye bye! またねー！
Bye bye! See you!
See you!
楽しいね、生ライブ！
This is fun, a live concert!
Oh man, this is so fun.
I just love singing.
I love singing live so much
and you guys, thank you for being a part of it.
Woo! Nailed it, you think so?
Because Sora-senpai was by my side.
It was awesome.
Now next, I'll be singing with a surprise secret guest,
but it's a bit of a break for myself and the band right now
because we're going to go back in time to...
a time when I recorded something with a special guest...
with the power of technology.
You'll understand what I mean but,
let's go back in the past and
myself and the band are going to chill for a minute.
So please enjoy that special guest performance
and I'll see you guys soon for the next live one
very shortly. Okay. See you then.
どうぞ！
Here you go!
罪と蜜 (feat. Mori Calliope)
[Title: Sin and Honey (feat. Mori Calliope)]
Case1
そう恋に落ちたんだけどきっと不幸に堕ちたんだ
I fell in love, but surely I fell into misfortune
気づきゃ僕らは行為に及んでいた
When I realized it, we had already engaged in the act
アナタの策 故意によるものだったんだ
It was part of your plan, intentional
見事さ
How magnificent
地獄への片道切符
A one-way ticket to hell
理性奪い去るリップ
Lip that steals away my reason
妄想 高揚 本能 暴走 So Mellow
Delusions, exaltation, instincts, running wild, So Mellow
さながら脳に数枚のチップ
Like burying several chips in the brain
埋め込む様な狂愛のキス
A kiss of mad love
"アタシ アタシの永久のVIP"
"I am your permanent VIP"
囁いた言葉ずっと離れずに
I'll never forget the words you whispered
アナタにアナタにアナタに
To you, to you, to you
相応しいヒトになれますか？
Can I become a person worthy of you?
Right you / Left me / 愛すyou
Right you / Left me / I love you
So we did it did it did it did it
Stop
I love you my girl / I love you my boy
アナタを知って全ては過去になる
Knowing you, everything becomes the past
I love you my girl / I love you my boy
しあーせに満ちた未来を作ろうね
Let's build a future filled with happiness
そう愛し切ってどうかこんな僕を
Yes, please love me until the end, this me
愛し切ってどうかこんなアタシを
Please love me until the end, this me
Give me Give me Give me Give me LOVE
Case2
ねぇアタシに退屈を着せないで
Hey, don't let me wear boredom
とびきりのドレスとアナタのエスコートで
With an exceptional dress and your escort
赤く染まる絨毯の上歩く
I walk on a carpet stained crimson
マムシじゃないけどアタシはスター
I'm not a viper, but I'm a star
どこまで行っても一番のお姫様 行くよ 3, 2, 1
No matter how far we go, I'm the #1 princess. Here we go! 3, 2, 1
That's on you 見せてあげる
That's on you, I'll show you.
周りない So in despair
With no surroundings, so in despair.
薔薇のタトゥー口移し流し込む罪の味
Mouth-to-mouth with a rose tattoo, pouring in the taste of sin.
共犯ね これであなたは
We're accomplices. Now you...
あたしに あたしに あたしに
...to me, to me, to me...
相応しい人になりました
...have become the perfect person.
Right you
Left me
Ice you
So we did it did it did it did it
Stop!
I love you, my God!
I love you, my boy!
I loveをもって あなたと僕 罪と罰
With 'I love', you and I, sin and punishment.
I love you, my God!
I love you, my boy!
その味知る前には戻れない
I can't go back to before I knew that taste.
愛してみて どうかこの僕を
Please, try to love me.
愛してみて どうかこのあたしを
君 君 君 君だ！
It's you, you, you, you!
Hey! Hey! Come on everybody! All right!
皆さん Welcome、SyudouさんとCalliope 3D Birthday Live!
Welcome everyone, to Syudou and Calliope's 3D Birthday Live!
壊し合うように 癒し合うように
As if breaking each other, as if healing each other.
求め合ってしまうのよ しょうがないじゃない
We end up wanting each other, it can't be helped, right?
与えられた天国より選んだ地獄
Better the hell we chose than the heaven we were given.
あなたと二人ならどこまで...！
If it's with you, then no matter how far...!
I love you, my God!
I love you, my boy!
ただ落ちていく
Just falling...
I love you, my God!
I love you, my boy!
あなたを知って全ては過去になる
Knowing you, everything becomes the past.
I love you, my God!
I love you, my boy!
幸せに満ちた未来を作ろうね
Let's create a future full of happiness.
愛しきって どうかこの僕を
Love me completely, please, love me.
愛しきって どうかこのあたしを
君 君 君 君だ！
It's you, you, you, you!
愛し合ってしまったこの僕ら
We who ended up loving each other.
ハッピーエンドに別れを告げ
Bid farewell to the happy ending.
君 君 君 君だ！
It's you, you, you, you!
アハ！皆さん、どう思いましたか？
A-ha! Everyone, what did you think?
ありがとうございます！
Thank you very much!
楽しかった！イェイイェイイェイ！
That was fun! Yay yay yay!
スーパースペシャルゲスト、Syudouさんが来ました！
Our super special guest, Syudou is here!
こんにちは！
Hello!
Dead Beatsの皆さんこんにちは、Syudouです。
Hello to all the Dead Beats, I'm Syudou.
Yes、自己紹介お願いします！
Yes, please introduce yourself!
はい、僕はですね、ミュージシャンやってます、Syudouでございます。
Yes, I'm Syudou, and I'm a musician.
そしてハッピーバースデー、Calliopeさん！おめでとうございます。
And happy birthday, Calliope! Congratulations.
Oh thank you! ありがとう！
Oh thank you! Thanks!
ライブも最高です。
The live is great too.
あ、ちなみにハイタッチしたいんですが...行きますか？
Oh, by the way, I want to do a high five... shall we?
あ、行きますか？
Oh, shall we?
はい！せーの！
Yes! One, two...!
よいしょ！ヘイ！
There! Hey!
いい感じ！ありがとうございます。
Feels good! Thank you very much.
ちなみにSyudouさんは、まぁ音楽活動いろいろやってますね？
By the way Syudou, you're doing various musical activities, right?
どのー、どの活動やってますか？
What- what kind of activities do you do?
そうですね、僕はボカロPですね。ボカロで楽曲を作ったり...
Well, I'm a Vocaloid P. I make songs with Vocaloid...
シンガーソングライターとして歌を歌わせていただいたり...
...sing as a singer-songwriter...
そして色々な方に楽曲を提供させたり、そんな活動をさせて頂いております。
...and provide songs to various people. Those are the kinds of activities I do.
イェイ！まぁもちろんあたし知ってるけど、なんか...大ファンだからね。
Yay! Well of course I know, since... I'm a big fan.
嬉しいです。ライブも以前来ていただきまして。
I'm happy. You also came to my live before.
そうですね。武道館ライブめっちゃ楽しかった！
That's right. The Budokan live was so much fun!
あーありがとう、本当僕も楽しくて、めちゃくちゃ盛り上がったんで...
Th- thank you, I also really had fun and it was so hyped...
嬉しいです今日出られて。
...so I'm happy to be here today.
こちらこそあたしもすごい嬉しいですね。
Likewise, I'm very happy too.
あの...このステージどう思いますか？
Um... what do you think of this stage?
ね、これすごいですよね、後ろからこの高さも含めて。
Right, this is amazing isn't it, including this height from the back.
僕ちょっと高い所苦手なんで落ちないように気をつけながらやらないとなと思うんですけど...
I'm a bit bad with high places so I feel like I have to be careful not to fall...
最高ですこれ、はい。
...but this is the best, yes.
まーかなり高いけど気をつけてね。
It's- quite high but be careful.
ちょっと高いですよね、下見えないから。やべー、はい。
It's a bit high isn't it, I can't see the bottom. Crap- yes.
え、でもそういえばなんかテーマが誕生日だから...
Oh, but speaking of which, since the theme is birthday...
ちょっと知りたいね、Syudouさんの誕生日はいつですか？
...I want to know a bit, when is your birthday, Syudou?
僕の誕生日 9月ですね、September。
My birthday is in September.
September！Septemberですね。
September! It is September.
お、SeptemberのBirthday Stone、誕生石はサファイアです。
Oh, the birthday stone for September is sapphire.
も、ほら、ステージはサファイア、サファイア、サファイアです！
Look, the stage is sapphire, sapphire, sapphire!
あ、そういうことだったのこれ、あーなるほど。
Ah, so that's what it was, ah I see.
僕に合わせていただいてありがとう、たまたまですけどあの服もこの青で帽子も青であったんで...
Thank you for matching it to me, even if by chance my clothes and hat were blue too...
相性がいい！
Good chemistry!
うわーめっちゃ嬉しいそうですね。ありがとうございます。
Wow- I'm very happy. Thank you very much.
やーすごい、めっちゃいい感じですね。
Yeah- amazing, it's a very good vibe.
いいですね、嬉しいです。
It's good, I'm happy.
Wow！え、次の曲は...
Wow! Um, the next song is...
Syudouさんが書き下ろしてくれたやつですね。
...one that Syudou wrote specifically for me.
そうですね。あの、僕がすごいCalliopeさんのもちろん楽曲大好きなんですけど...
That's right. Um, I really love Calliope's songs of course, but...
Calliopeさんのこうかっこよくて、強くて、すごい美しいみたいな所を引き出せるような楽曲として作らせて頂いた曲でございますね。
...it's a song I created to bring out Calliope's cool, strong, and beautiful sides.
はい。
Yes.
ありがとう！やーめっちゃいい曲本当に何か大好きな曲だから。
Thank you! Yeah- it's a really good song, I really love it.
嬉しい、ありがとう。
I'm happy, thank you.
マジ本当に感謝してます。
I'm really grateful.
はいありがとうございます。
Yes, thank you.
今回一緒に歌いたいと思います。
I'd like for us to sing together this time.
初めてですね一緒に歌うのはこれはね。
This is the first time we're singing together.
初めてです。なかなかレアなのではないでしょうか。
It's the first time. Isn't this quite rare?
大丈夫ですか？
Are you ready?
はいありがとうございます。
Yes, thank you.
Okay、じゃ次の曲に行く前に、皆に伝えたいことありますか？
Okay, before we go to the next song, is there anything you want to tell everyone?
はい、えーそうですね、僕こうCalliopeさんと何度かコラボさせて頂いてるんですけど...
Yes, well, I've collaborated with Calliope several times...
Dead Beatsの皆さん含め本当にもう温かく迎えて頂いて...
...and everyone, including the Dead Beats, has welcomed me so warmly...
すごい嬉しいです。で今回ライブもこうやってやらせて頂いて...
...so I'm very happy. And to be able to do this live too...
皆一緒に盛り上がって...！
...everyone get hyped together...!
...聴いてくれたら嬉しいですし、
...I'd be happy if you listened to it, and
改めてカリオペさん、呼んでくれてありがとうございます。
once again, Calliope-san, thank you for inviting me.
いえいえ、こちらこそ！
No, no, the pleasure is mine!
じゃあ、それで聴いてくださいね。
Well then, please listen to it.
でもシドウさん、紹介してください！
But Shido-san, please introduce it!
はい。それではお聴きください、
Yes. Then please listen,
LET'S JUST CRASH!
Hey, hey, 皆さん！
Hey, hey, everyone!
Yeah!
Let's go!
Ha-ha-ha-ha
Hey! Hey!
Let's go!
Hey, you got eyes and ears, but you don't look or listen
In other words, you're useless, every last one of ya
And that's why I'm gonna send you all to hell
All of humanity, hell
Woah!
声援背負い颯爽と登場
Swooping in while carrying the cheers
そういうんじゃねぇ
It's not like that
I'm just the type you'd forget
So don't waste your time
千切れ腐りかけの chain,
A torn and rotting chain,
going insane, somebody's gotta pay
While I live with the pain, laugh at me now,
I'm the one you can't tame, huh
低俗で最低の天才
A low-class, bottom-tier genius
そういうんでいい
That's fine by me
想いが募る
Feelings gather
場所に花は咲くから
Because flowers bloom in that place
(Let's riot)
(Get back, you're trash)
掃き溜めで希望を
In the dumpster of hope
(Let's just crash)
積み上げていくんだ
We'll keep piling it up
頂から高らかに笑え
Laugh loudly from the summit
(Lose control)
(Heads will roll)
美しき理想を
A beautiful ideal
汚してくる野郎は
The bastard who comes to defile it
誰だ一体？
Who the hell is it?
誰だったとしても
No matter who it might be
この理想は無理だろって
Even if they say this ideal is impossible
誰が言ったとしても叶えてこうぜ
No matter who says it, let's make it happen
Hey! Hey!
Goodbye!
Yeah!
Get back!
Versus!
Listen!
正解不正解の解答
Answers to what's right and wrong
どうだっていい
I don't care about any of that
そんなとっくのとうに
Long ago, in a place
超えた場所に俺は立っている
Beyond all that, I am standing
Yeah, meaningless problems, everybody's got 'em
And they can't be satisfied until somebody's at the bottom,
so what?
You think you're special 'cause you got some grit and hunger?
We ain't getting any younger,
thinking let's just crash
心が通う
Our hearts connect
時に魂が叫ぶ
The times when our souls scream
(Hoo-hoo)
Woo-hoo!
(Get back, you're trash)
ドブネズミの様に
Like a sewer rat
(Let's just crash)
気高く生きるんだ
Living with pride
俺が通る今すぐに退け
I'm passing through, out of my way right now
(Let's riot)
(Get back, you're trash)
掃き溜めで希望を
In the dumpster of hope
(Let's just crash)
積み上げていくんだ
We'll keep piling it up
頂から高らかに笑え
Laugh loudly from the summit
(Lose control)
(Heads will roll)
美しき理想を
A beautiful ideal
汚してくる野郎は
The bastard who comes to defile it
誰だ一体？
Who the hell is it?
誰だったとしても
No matter who it might be
この理想は無理だろって
Even if they say this ideal is impossible
誰が言ったとしても
No matter who says it,
叶えてこうぜ
let's make it happen
Oh-oh, woah-oh
Woah-oh!
Come on!
3, 2, 1, let's go!
Hey! Hey!
Woo!
シドウさんありがとうございました！
Shido-san, thank you very much!
Thank you Calliope!
Yeah, yeah!
叶えてこうぜ
Let's make it happen
でもまだまだ終わってないっすね、皆さん！
But we're not finished yet, everyone!
All right! LET'S JUST CRASH!
ありがとうございました！バイバイ、シドウさん！
Thank you very much! Bye-bye, Shido-san!
バイバイ！サンキュー、デッドビーツ、アンド、カリオペ！
Bye-bye! Thank you, Dead Beats, and Calliope!
Yeah, yeah! Peace!
ああ、皆さん、楽しかったですね。
Ah, everyone, that was so fun.
シドウさんをアーティストとして本当に尊敬しています。
I really respect Shido-san as an artist.
彼は多くの作業を自分自身でこなしているんです、
He does a lot of his work himself for his songs,
作詞作曲、歌唱、すべて。本当にカッコいいですよね。
you know, writes and composes and sings and everything. He's really cool.
シドウさんに大きな拍手を！
So, big ups to Shido-san.
さて、そろそろ未来に戻る時間かな？
But I think it is about time that maybe we get back to the future?
それとも現在？友達みんなとパフォーマンスしている場所へ。うーん、そうですね。
The present? Where I'm performing with all my friends right now. Hmm. Yes.
でも本当に楽しかったです。そして...
But that was a lot of fun. And...
ああ、やっぱり。
ah, as I thought.
時間通りだ。
Right on time.
未来に戻る時間のようです。
It looks like it's time for me to get back to the future
そして友達みんなともう一度歌う時間だ。
and go sing with all my friends again.
現在で...未来で...よくわからないけど、
Back in the present... future... I don't know,
わけがわからないですね。行きましょう！
it doesn't make any sense. Let's go!
あちらで会いましょう！
See you there!
Blue World
Lyrics: Nerissa Ravencroft
Music, Arrangement: 目黒将司
[Song: Blue World]
[Lyrics: Nerissa Ravencroft]
[Music, Arrangement: Shoji Meguro]
Walking an empty road, nowhere for me to go
Walking an empty road
Nowhere for me to go
Lost and lonely
Yeah it's only me
Burnt out like candle light
Left blazing through the night
Melting slowly
Until nothing else is left of me
Colored in shades of grey
Watching the days pass in front of me
Longing to find a way
I can fly away
I'm drifting through this blue, blue world
It's always been clear to me
How cruel the world can be
My shadow's the only one beside me
No love to call my own
No notifs on my phone
Sunken silence
Has engulfed the very life I lead
Colored in shades of grey
Watching the years pass in front of me
Memories I wish would stay
Always fade away
I'm lonely in this blue, blue world
Though my heart is torn
And my weary wings are worn
Just tonight, can't I dream of a better life
With happiness in sight?
Colored in shades of grey
Watching my life pass in front of me
Maybe it's not too late
If I can't escape
I'll have to make my own way
Colored in shades of grey
Palette in hand, I can make a change
I'll try to find the strength
Take a breath and paint
Bring color to this blue, blue world
Wow, beautiful Nerissa! You're so great!
Ah! Thank you for coming!
Thank you for having me!
After that emotional song, now we're all energetic!
Oh my god, hi everybody!
Hey! High-energy everyone!
Thank you, thank you, it is my birthday!
But who is this lovely lady I'm singing with right now?
Who could I be? Hi darlings!
This is Hololive English Advent's devilish diva,
the one, the only, Nerissa Ravencroft,
here with you today at your birthday party!
Wow! かっこいい！ So cool!
Wow! So cool! So cool!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you very much!
You're so awesome, Nerissa.
Thank you so much...
...for letting me sing your Shojo Meguro song together with you!
We both love Shojo Meguro!
We both have a Shojo Meguro original song!
Yes we both do!
I'm happy that my first time performing it...
...got to be with you.
Yeah, no seriously, it was so fun.
It's always fun singing with a friend, so thank you for letting me be a part of it.
We got to harmonize too!
Yes!
I did my best to learn the harmonies and...
...you know, try and remember and stay consistent.
You did amazing.
You impressed me.
Thank you so much.
Well, I guess we gotta talk about your birthstone...
...'cause now we're gonna talk about your birthday even though it's my birthday.
Yeah yeah.
Do you know your birthstone's a topaz?
Yes!
It's so pretty.
My birthday is November 21st...
I'm a Scorpio...
...and it's so pretty!
It matches my...
...your little hair clip.
So true.
My gosh, it just positively lights you up...
...you're glowing.
How about we take some pictures in front of the stone?
Oh yeah, let's do it.
Let's do it!
All right, here we go.
Peace... peace... peace...
どっちでも。
Either one's good.
Oh, facing each other.
Feel a little sexy.
Oh, boy!
いい感じ！
Looking good!
Very nice.
いい感じ。
Looking good.
Use the hashtag!
Yes, please.
Please use the hashtag lots and post lots of pictures, okay?
Actually, just so you know, Nerissa...
...Genta on the drums is the one who played for our original song, Override.
Oh my God!
Thank you!
Arigato!
You're amazing!
Genta, thank you!
So awesome, really appreciate you. Thank you.
So many wonderful band members and guests, I feel very lucky and privileged...
...and lucky to have you.
Thank you, Calli.
Do you want to drink a water before we start?
That's a great idea, let's do that.
Yeah?
Immediately.
Yes.
お水
Water
Okay, yay, I think we're ready for another song then, how about that?
I am too, let's do it.
Okay, together we can do anything.
Yes.
Next up is a Calliope original song...
...please enjoy, Orpheus.
Orpheus
Lyrics: Mori Calliope / Music: Koichi Tsuruya
Arrangement: Koichi Tsuruya, Kazuma Nagasawa
[Song: Orpheus / Lyrics: Mori Calliope / Music: Koichi Tsuruya / Arrangement: Koichi Tsuruya, Kazuma Nagasawa]
All right! Thank you so much Nerissa for coming to hang out!
Let's finish this off with a bang!
Here we go!
I ain't trying to stress you, I must confess though
My heart's beating to your song
(Oh yeah)
Thinking, "Hurry up Orpheus, time's a wasting
(Show me what you really wanna do?)"
Another late night, endless dreaming
The day to day starts to call
Still got like a million deadlines, still bleeding red wine
My back up against the wall
I got my headphones on, walk home is long
Dragging feet like I'm born to lose
'Til somehow they're tapping along, to you know who's song
A melody I can't refuse
I'm outta line but it's fine, you don't know my name
Safe inside my own mind, I don't feel the shame, okay?
I know I get a little carried away
But we got music when there aren't any words to say
'Cause in my heart, feel a spark when you look this way
Gimme a sign from the stage when you feel the same
Now I'm in distress, you got me possessed, I might be obsessed
So let me get a little something off my chest
Look, I ain't trying to stress you, I must confess though
My heart's beating to your song
(Oh yeah)
Thinking, "Hurry up Orpheus, time's a wasting
(Show me what you really wanna do?)"
Tonight it's my turn to show you how obvious I can be
Sometimes it feels like you're playing that guitar for me and only me
Critic so loud, so predictable, they can't see what I can see
You're gonna wind up a star, you got me dancing so bizarre
This distance got me feeling fonder, I wonder if it's enough
'Cause I'm not lying when I'm implying you're all that I've been thinking of
Maybe they'll call me delusional, baby, this could be real love?
Give me one chance and I'll take, you make me dance the night away
(Get us help, guh)
Now it's a game that I've played before but with the way the scene changed
There is nothing you can blame me for
I'm talking TV screens, magazines, seen you in a couple dreams
Pictures up on every padded wall and floor
Always talking bad about time to desire a lover
So why'd you paint your nails up in my favorite color?
I gotta add it soon, just when it comes to you
See our reality is kind of slipping at its noon
I'm never lost in the groove of somebody new
If it's a function you're after I'm staying true
So are you noticing me noticing you noticing me?
Not delusional but there's not a lot of guarantee
'Cause in my heart feel a spark when you look this way
Gimme a sign from the stage when you feel the same
You're strumming next to me and I'm in ecstasy
And for the rest of the week I'm the pressure-free
All right!
I ain't trying to stress you, I must confess though
My heart's beating to your song
(Oh yeah)
Thinking, "Hurry up Orpheus, time's a wasting
(Show me what you really wanna do?)"
Tonight it's my turn to show you just how obvious I can be
So just as long as you keep playing that guitar
For me and only me
(Gah-hi-ya!)
Critic so loud, so predictable, they can't see what I can see
You're gonna wind up a star, you got me dancing so bizarre
This distance got me feeling fonder, I wonder if it's enough
'Cause I'm not lying when I'm implying you're all that I've been thinking of
Maybe they'll call me delusional, baby, this could be real love?
Give me one chance and I'll take, you make me dance the night away
Hey, hey!
All right everybody!
Today we have a very special band that's gathered today!
They're so cool!
Right!
We gotta give them a proper introduction, Nerissa!
Yes we do!
So let's do it!
Are you guys ready to meet the band?
Here we go!
First up on the drums we got Genta!
[Drums: 白川 玄太]
[Drums: Genta Shirakawa]
Then on the bass it's Yu Park!
[Bass: Yu Park]
And on the guitar is Yoshi!
[Guitar: 芳賀 義彦]
[Guitar: Yoshihiko Haga]
And last but not least, tonight's manipulator is Hana!
All right Nerissa, let's take 'em out!
Sounds good? Here we go!
Orpheus, get me go and taking space
with the bass and drum
So let's blow this joint and if the feelings fight
then we can make a little music of our own tonight.
Orpheus, get me go and taking space
with the bass and drum
Why you walking away? I got a lot to say.
Guess I'll save it up for the next one. Whoo!
I ain't tryna stress you, I must confess though,
my heart's been turned to ice.
Oh yeah, so hear me out Orpheus, I'm thinking
next time I'll show you what I really wanna do.
Bye Nerissa! Thanks for singing with me!
Have a good rest of your birthday! Love you!
Yes! See you later, love you too, bye-bye!
ねえあたしいつも勇気が足りないから
Hey, I'm always lacking courage,
自分を大切にできないんだ
so I can't cherish myself.
痛い目をみないと気付けやしないんだ
I won't notice unless I have a painful experience.
あーあ今日もキャラメルペインです
Ah, ah, it's Caramel Pain again today.
[曲：キャラメルペイン / 作詞・作曲：DECO*27]
[Song: Caramel Pain / Lyrics, Music: DECO*27]
良い子でなんかいられないよ
I can't just be a good girl,
だって世界はこんなにも極彩色で
because the world is so colorful,
甘ったるくて苦いし あ、待って頭痛いし
cloyingly sweet and bitter. Ah, wait, my head hurts...
ヘトヘトで漂うだけの24/7
and I'm just drifting, 24/7.
ギリギリ感情おさえるなんてもう無理
It's impossible to suppress my barely-held emotions.
このままではいられないの日々
These days, I can't stay like this.
ちょっとこわいけど...
It's a little scary, but...
置いてくよ置いてくよ置いてくよ
I'll leave them behind, leave them behind.
今まで手にしたイデオロギーもスタイルも
Even the ideologies and styles I held until now...
壊れちゃっても今がいいよ
even if they break, right now is fine,
だってあたしはあたしのままでずっといたいんだもん
because I want to stay as I am forever.
ルート? ムード? どうでもいーよトゥーザネクスト
Route? Mood? Who cares? To the next,
もっと危ないことしたら勝ちなんでしょ
if I do more dangerous things, I win, right?
何を犠牲にしたってしょうがないんだよ
Whatever I have to sacrifice, it can't be helped.
フロムマイベッド この胸の痛みだけ抱いて
From my bed, just hugging the pain in this chest.
あーあ今日もキャラメルペインです
Ah, ah, it's Caramel Pain again today.
ミルフィーユみたいにはぐらかしたって
Even if I dodge it like a mille-feuille,
いつかバレちゃうよ 腐っちゃうよ
it'll be exposed someday. It'll rot, it'll rot.
痛いとか素直に君に言えてれば
If I could have honestly told you it was painful,
今頃何か変わってたのかもね
maybe something would have changed by now.
好きなアニメもなくなっちゃうし
The anime I like will disappear,
好きな人だっていなくなっちゃうんだ
and the person I like will disappear too.
寂しくなっちゃうな
That makes me lonely.
大切なことは ただ一つだけさ
The important thing is just one thing.
もう後悔しないように前を向いて生きるということ!
So I don't have any more regrets, I'll live looking forward!
置いてくよ置いてくよ置いてくよ
I'll leave them behind, leave them behind.
今まで手にしたイデオロギーもスタイルも
Even the ideologies and styles I held until now...
汚れちゃっても気にしないよ
even if they get dirty, I don't care,
だってあたしはあたしに恋してたいんだもん
because I want to be in love with myself.
愛してるよ愛してるよ愛してるよ
I love you, I love you, I love you.
さよならなんて涙が出ちゃうけど
Saying goodbye makes me tear up, but...
何を犠牲にしたってしょうがないんだよ
whatever I have to sacrifice, it can't be helped.
フロムマイベッド この胸の痛みだけ抱いて
From my bed, just hugging the pain in this chest.
あーあ今日もキャラメルペインです
Ah, ah, it's Caramel Pain again today.
ねえあたしいつも勇気が足りないから
Hey, I'm always lacking courage,
自分を大切にできないんだ
so I can't cherish myself.
痛いくらいなら少し我慢するんだ
If it hurts, I'll just endure it a little.
あーあ今日もキャラメルペインです
Ah, ah, it's Caramel Pain again today.
イェーイ！すいせい先輩きた！
Yay! Suisei-sempai came!
やったー！最高！やったー！
Yeah! The best! We did it!
久しぶりですけど、おめでとう！
It's been a while, but congrats!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
自己紹介お願いします。
Self-introduction please.
彗星の如く現れたスターの原石、
アイドルVTuberの星街すいせいです！
I'm the diamond in the rough,
the idol VTuber Hoshimachi Suisei!
カリオペ、誕生日おめでとう！
Calliope, happy birthday!
ありがとうございます！誕生日です！
Thank you! It's my birthday!
そしてね、メジャーデビューも4周年！
And also, it's the 4th anniversary of your major debut!
そうですよ、長い！おめでとう！
That's right! Wow, it's been a long time, congrats!
一緒に歌いましたよ。
We sang together!
そう、4年前ね！
Yeah, 4 years ago!
メジャーデビューした時の...
When we made our major debut...
ライブで...
At the live...
一緒に歌わせてもらいましたね。
We got to sing together.
懐かしい。
Nostalgic.
ねえ、懐かしい。これ... なんかこんなんもやってなくない？
Right, nostalgic. This... didn't we do something like this?
やりました。たくさんやりました。
We did. We did it a lot.
ヤバいよね。めっちゃいい思い出ですよね。
It's crazy, right? It's a really good memory.
わあ、覚えてくれたね、それ。
Wow, you remembered that, didn't you?
久しぶりに歌えて嬉しいね。
I'm happy we could sing it after a long time.
懐かしいポイント。
Nostalgic point.
ありがとう。
Thank you.
そうですね、今回「Caramel Pain」一緒に歌いました。
That's right, we sang "Caramel Pain" together this time.
一番好きな星街すいせい曲です！
It's my favorite Hoshimachi Suisei song!
わあ、嬉しい！
Wow, I'm happy!
イェーイ、やった。
Yay, we did it.
めっちゃいい感じだったね。ハモリとかもね。
It felt really good. The harmonies and all.
たくさん練習しました。
We practiced a lot.
ねえ、本当に綺麗だったぜ。
Yeah, it was really beautiful.
ありがとうございます。
Thank you very much.
ちなみに、ほら、ピカピカ・ストーン。
By the way, look, a shiny stone.
Wow, beautiful. 素敵ですよね。
Wow, beautiful. It's lovely, isn't it?
So taking.
So breathtaking.
え、すいせい先輩。あたし知ってるけど、誕生日はいつですか？
Um, Suisei-senpai. I know, but when is your birthday?
私は3月の22！
Mine is March 22nd!
March 22nd. March 22nd.
イェーイ、そうですね。
Yay, that's right.
うん... 先月、先月...
Um... last month, last month...
超先月。
Just last month.
Yes. ですので...
Yes. So...
ほら、アクアマリンが誕生石。
Look, Aquamarine is the birthstone.
アクアマリンだ！
It's Aquamarine!
もうぴったりよね。私知らなかったよ、自分の誕生石アクアマリンって。
It fits perfectly. I didn't know my birthstone was Aquamarine.
そう、ぴったりですよ。マジで最高。
Yes, it's perfect. Seriously, the best.
同じ色だよもう。
It's the same color already.
同じ色です。
Same color.
最高だぜ。
It's the best.
めっちゃ素敵ですよ。
It's very lovely.
めっちゃ綺麗から、一緒に写真撮りましょう。
It's so beautiful, let's take a photo together.
あ、撮ろう！
Oh, let's take one!
いいですか？
Is it okay?
Let's go!
Yeah!
私ね、やりたいものある。
I have something I want to do.
OK, what?
OK, let's do it! Yeah!
これわかる？何のポーズか。
Do you know what this is? What pose this is.
No, ジョジョじゃない？
No, isn't it JoJo?
違うよ。
No.
What's this?
Golden Belt! あ、そうだ！
Golden Belt! Oh, that's right!
そう！
Yes!
これかっこいいよね。
This is cool, isn't it?
ありがとう。
Thank you.
Thank you so much. え、ちゃんと見てくれた。ありがとう。
Thank you so much. Um, you watched it properly. Thank you.
もちろん！大好きな曲ですよ。
Of course! It's a song I love.
Thank you so much, senpai.
え、ちなみに、everybody really quick, before we keep going, おしらせあります。
Um, by the way, everybody really quick, before we keep going, there's an announcement.
Yes, quick announcement about members only. メンバー限定、アンコールがありますよ。
Yes, quick announcement about members only. There's a members-only encore.
やったー！
Yay!
A solo session. And we need to pick one song that I just performed with the amazing guests and I'm going to do a solo version of it. Yes.
So you have one minute starting now. 1分ありますよ、vote!
So you have one minute starting now. You have one minute, vote!
▼この後のメンバーシップ限定で歌う楽曲がどれがいいか１つ選んで投票してね！▼
[Vote for the song you want to hear me sing in the upcoming members-only stream!]
あの、カリオペはソロで歌いますよ。
Um, Calliope will sing solo.
さっきゲストと一緒に歌った曲。 Please vote everybody, you have one minute, go!
The songs I sang with guests earlier. Please vote everybody, you have one minute, go!
えー、なんとなんと。
Oh, wow.
めんげんで、このあとのめんげんでソロで歌ってくれるらしいですよ。
In the members-only stream, in the upcoming members-only stream, she's going to sing solo.
Yes!
え、全部聞きたいよ！
Eh, I want to hear them all!
そうだね。全部めっちゃめっちゃいい曲、すべての。
Right. They're all very, very good songs, all of them.
ねえ！ヤバいよ。
Right! It's crazy.
でも、1曲だけ。 Only one.
But, only one song. Only one.
ねえ、1曲だけですよ。
Right, only one song.
選んでくださいね。選んでね。
Please choose. Choose one.
Please お願いします。
Please, I beg you.
どれがいいかな、どれがいいかな。OK.
Which one should it be, which one should it be. OK.
お願いします。あー、楽しみ、頑張ります。
Please. Ah, I'm looking forward to it, I'll do my best.
ふんふん... カリオペ本当になあ...
Hmm... Calliope really...
よ... 4年。メジャーデビューして4年。
Four... four years. Four years since major debut.
本当に駆け抜けてきたよね、すいせいさん。
We've really run through it, haven't we, Suisei-san.
うん, いろいろやってますよ。
Yes, we've done various things.
なんかアニメのタイアップとかもね、たくさん決まって。
Like many anime tie-ups have been decided too.
来ました。来ました。
They have. They have.
ねえ、嬉しい。
Right, I'm happy.
So my dream. そうですね、夢がかなった。
So my dream. That's right, my dream came true.
えー、すごいめっちゃ嬉しい。ありがとうございます。
Eh, I'm very happy. Thank you very much.
皆さんのおかげで。
Thanks to everyone.
素敵な先輩のおかげでも。
Also thanks to my wonderful senpai.
My inspiration.
Thank you so much, everybody.
Yay!
So keep shooting for the moon. Yeah.
そうだよ。
That's right.
うん、 let's see.
Um, let's see.
Oh OK. Well, everybody's writing what they want. Oh OK, すごいすごい。
Oh OK. Well, everybody's writing what they want. Oh OK, amazing, amazing.
今好きな曲... おーすごいすごい。
Favorite songs now... oh amazing, amazing.
Many many many many.
あ、投票がだんだん...
Ah, the voting is gradually...
Go go go! Choose choose choose! 選んで選んで！
Go go go! Choose choose choose! Choose, choose!
選んだ？
Have you chosen?
始めてる？
Has it started?
投票もう少し長くやりますってよ。
They say they'll keep the voting open a little longer.
うん, OK. A little bit longer.
Um, OK. A little bit longer.
Longer longer time.
Yes, please choose one. It's hard, 難しいと思うけど。
Yes, please choose one. It's hard, I think it's difficult.
イェーイ。
Yay.
えー、 let's drink water.
Um, let's drink water.
あ、確かに。
Ah, certainly.
水乾杯。いいですか？
Water toast. Is it okay?
飲みましょう、はい。
Let's drink, yes.
OK.
Cheers! Cheers!
んー。
Mmm.
Thank you senpai. Japanese 'Cheers' なんだと思う？
Thank you senpai. What do you think Japanese 'Cheers' is?
んー、乾杯。
Mmm, Kanpai.
乾杯。 Yes.
Kanpai. Yes.
最近の流行りなんて言うと思う？
What do you think the recent trend is called?
あー、 cheers?
Ah, cheers?
ケーピ！
KEPI!
ケーピ！そうですね、えーたくさん使いたいと思う。
KEPI! That's right, um, I want to use it a lot.
使ってください。
Please use it.
乾杯だけじゃなくケーピ。
Not just Kanpai but KEPI.
ケーピ！
KEPI!
ヘイヘイ、パリピが使ってますよ。
Hey hey, party people are using it.
パリピ。
Party people.
カリオペパリピじゃないけど、使います。使います。
Calliope isn't a party person, but I'll use it. I'll use it.
パリピ。
Party people.
えーパリピ in the house let's go.
Eh, party people in the house let's go.
いいっすね。
That's good.
Nice.
All right, is the voting closed?
どうかなどうかな？
I wonder?
決まったかな決まったかな？
Is it decided?
あ、決まったかな？ちょっとわかんない。
Ah, is it decided? I don't really know.
どうですか皆さん？お水おいしいだって。
How about it everyone? They say the water is delicious.
おいしい？
Is it delicious?
Oh, close?
あ、ふー...
Ah, phew...
フワモコ、フワモコ見てくれてる？
FuwaMoco, FuwaMoco, are you watching?
Hi FuwaMoco! Thanks for coming! I love FuwaMoco!
あ、今からスタート？
Oh, are we starting now?
今からスタート！
Starting now!
Okay, no problem. Push, push!
Go, go, go! Push, please!
ちなみにカリオペの他のお知らせがあるんだけど...
By the way, I have another announcement...
カバー曲もリリースします！
I'm releasing a cover song, too!
Yes, check it out! The cover song is "In My Head" by NATOLI.
Check it out, "In My Head"!
I like song!
I like that song!
You like it? Yeah!
In my head! In my head!
Please listen to it! 聴いてくださいね！
Please listen to it! Please give it a listen!
そう、このライブのあと、そしてそのあとは...
Right, after this live, and after that...
メンバー限定！
It's members-only!
Yes! And we have goods!
Goods are going to be released very soon, so I wanted to tell you guys about them.
グッズもありますので！Limited!
We have goods available! Limited edition!
Limitedもありますので、ちゃんとお伝えしたかったけど...
There's limited merch, so I really wanted to tell you...
最後の方、配信の最後の方はCMを流します！
At the end, at the end of the stream, we'll play a CM!
But in about two minutes, 本当にもうすぐ...
But in about two minutes, it's really coming soon...
出るから、そのURLをツイートするから...
It's coming out, and I'll tweet the URL...
準備しといて！
So get ready!
Ready? 心も準備して。
Ready? Get your heart ready, too.
[Title: Mori Calliope Birthday 2026 Merchandise]
Oh, check it out! Here they are!
かっこいい！
So cool!
Dark fantasy Calliope! Dark fantasy!
Thank you! I'm so cool! I'm like...
すっごい... あの魔王みたい！
Amazing... like a Demon King!
Yes! 魔王 is English what?
Yes! What's "Maou" in English?
魔王... uh... like... なんて言えばいいかな？
Demon King... uh... like... how should I say it?
Dark... Dark King? Dark King!
Dark King! Yes, Dark King!
英語上手いよ、すごい！
Your English is so good, wow!
あ、投票終了。Voting is over, by the way!
Oh, voting is over. Voting is over, by the way!
Voting is over! It's done! Yay!
Thank you so much. Oh my god, I'm excited to see what you guys chose.
Now then, we should sing one more song then, shouldn't we?
But look out for the goods! Goods URL is dropping soon, there's limited merch.
チェックしてね、グッズ買って！
Check it out, and buy some goods!
よろしくお願いします！
Please support us!
Okay, so... たくさん休みましたね！
Okay, so... we took a long break!
So let's sing one more song!
もう一曲一緒に歌いたいと思います！
I want to sing one more song together!
いいですか皆さん？！
Are you ready, everyone?!
ん、じゃあ二人ならやれるさ！
Mmm, then the two of us can do it!
Next song is... "Gold Unbalance"!
[Title: Gold Unbalance feat. Kento Nakajima]
不確かな物語に勝ち取るはアイデンティティー
Winning back my identity in an uncertain story
あれやこれと手を替え品を替え
Trying this and that, switching tactics and items
ドキりと胸を刺す激情
A sudden rush of passion that stabs the heart
感情はノンフィクションで喜怒哀楽
Emotions are non-fiction: joy, anger, sorrow, and pleasure
一心同体一切合切の衝動
Body and soul as one, an all-encompassing impulse
失敗も成功も味わえ
Savor both failure and success
我らゴールデンバディ
We are the Golden Buddies
意味なんてないような世界で
In a world that seems to have no meaning
偶然を重ねた光
The light formed by layered coincidences
脈打つ鼓動
The throbbing pulse
誰にもなれない言葉を紡いでよ
Spin words that no one else can
舐めんじゃねーよ
Don't mess with us
小さな勇気ひとつありゃ十分
Just a single spark of courage is enough
強気に高みへと
Confidently reaching for the heights
圧倒　絶頂
Overwhelming, at the peak
2人ならやれるさ
If it's the two of us, we can do it
Back-to-back, no matter what
背負ったもん武器に変わるSpot
The place where our burdens become our weapons
段違い　遠くまで飛ばすShout
On another level, sending our shouts far away
誰も邪魔できねぇこのRout
No one can block this route
1等2等3通りって
1st place, 2nd place, 3 ways...
はなからLoser
A loser from the very start
うざいくらい貪欲にハート地獄からかっぱらっちまえ
Snatch their hearts from hell with annoying greed
Loop輪廻じゃない
It's not a loop of reincarnation
Routeは無限に
The routes are infinite
ありふれた道じゃない荊の道を好む玄人
An expert who prefers the thorny path over the common one
A-ha-ha-ha!
盛大にもう笑えばいいさ
Go ahead and laugh out loud
才能煩脳のグラデーション
A gradation of talent and worldly desires
どうせならぐちゃぐちゃにしてよ
Might as well make a mess of it all
始めたのならやり切る覚悟を
If you've started, be prepared to finish
敗者と勝者のDuet
A duet of winners and losers
劣等感弾き出された不条理の屑
Scraps of absurdity cast out by inferiority complexes
振り払え貪欲に志は消えない
Shake it off greedily; our will won't vanish
2人ならやれるさ
If it's the two of us, we can do it
生きるってなんだサボった者勝ちか
What does it mean to live? Is laziness the winner?
そんなもの握りつぶせ
Crush thoughts like that
上辺じゃいられない
I can't stay on the surface
エンタメライダー
Entertainment Rider
人生賭け　駆け抜け
Betting my life as I run through
絶望も栄光も
Through both despair and glory
Lemme see you fight back
どうなったって何も変わらないんだって
Saying nothing changes no matter what happens
ミームされた現実に囚われて
Trapped in a memed reality
This life where we're stuck taking chances
飽き飽きしてんでしょ？？
You're sick of it, aren't you??
We're living in a world with no direction
Reach out with our light 'till we make a connection
Tearing the walls apart
Facing it all, side by side
Once again, it's us against the world
舐めんじゃねーよ
Don't underestimate us!
本能をヒリつかせて
Let your instincts tingle,
本物見せつけろ
and show them the real thing!
圧倒
Overwhelming...
絶頂
climax!
アンバランスを踊れ
Dance the unbalance!
踊れ
Dance!
Thanks for watching everyone! Thank you to my guests!
Thank you to the band! Thank you everyone!
Come hang out at members gentei!
Come hang out at the members-only after-show!
Okay, 後のもよろしく！
Okay, look forward to the rest!
Yeah, and 5 is good!
That's about all you guys, I'm Mori Calliope, peace out, see ya!
Woo! Let's go! Yeah!
Bye!
Hah, what's up you crazy skeleton...
Mori Calliope Birthday 2026
[Visual: Mori Calliope Birthday 2026]
I mean, dearest deadbeats, the hour is finally upon us.
The sale of Mori Calliope's birthday celebration goods is about to begin.
誕生日記念 2026
[Visual: Birthday Celebration 2026]
On this most auspicious day, you've been granted a great blessing by Death herself.
A most fortunate occurrence for thee, that such a glorious chest should appear before thine eyes.
Let's take a peek at what the Goddess of Death herself has to offer, shall we?
The journey ahead is long and arduous. It would do thee good to prepare for it with such luxurious treasures.
死の永遠の寵愛に抱かれて - ブランケット
[Embraced by Death's Eternal Favor - Blanket]
Firstly, wouldst thou find comfort in dear Death's embrace? If it be so...
...take some warmth along thy journey with this very large rollable blanket featuring a most intimidating maiden.
Yours truly, designed by my favorite dark fantasy artist, Shimhag! Woo!
The maiden in question possesses artworks en masse from this particular individual, so I'd be most elated if you bought it.
Lay it across your bed, hang it on your wall, take it with you on an outing, think of the possibilities!
死の祝福の護符 - ランダムラバーストラップ
[Amulet of Death's Blessing - Random Rubber Strap]
Secondly, whilst on thy noble journey, thou mayst come to need a spark of aid.
If it be so, take one of these amulets. The emblem of a knight to boost your strength.
The emblem of a samurai to grant you additional dexterity.
The emblem of a priestess to bestow additional health to thy weary body.
And lastly, the emblem of a necromancer to grant thee additional intelligence.
Alas, as fortune be a fickle mistress, thou may only receive one in a set.
I pray thee be granted the boon most favorable to thy quest.
Or, or you could just purchase them all separately if you're looking to speedrun the experience, I suppose.
幸運の休息のランタン
[Lantern of Fortunate Respite]
Thirdly, I present to thee the shining centerpiece of this valuable collection.
Take a moment of repose and sit beside this warm and healing light, granted unto thee by Death herself.
A lantern to revive thee as many times as needed throughout even the most daunting of journeys.
May it light thy way to victory, or to sweet dreams, whichever is preferred.
Enjoy an elegant design chosen specifically by myself.
再生の癒しのグラス
[Healing Flask of Regeneration (Glass)]
And of course, how could one continue a journey into vast and unforgiving lands without a source of healing?
Rejuvenate thyself with this generous flask, or rather glass, that seems to refill endlessly upon rest at your lantern.
At least, I think it will. There really are no guarantees in this life, but give it a try yourself.
Enjoy your favorite beverage during a night of exploring your favorite fantasy scenarios.
シチュエーションボイス: 「失われた者への死の神聖なる裁き」
[Situational Voice: "Divine Sanction Upon the Lost One"]
But naturally, it'd do me no good to leave thee without, I don't know, a bedtime story.
To put this enchanting collection into context, so please enjoy a short audiobook-style recording of a fantastical story.
Believe it or not, we are the stars of this tale, so enjoy it on a rainy evening wrapped warmly in Death's embrace.
The, the blanket I mean. You can use the flask also for drinking at the same time. You should really buy the full set.
フルセット購入特典
[Full Set Purchase Bonus]
And definitely do, because lucky skeletons who act fast and purchase the entire set will be granted a hand-signed postcard...
...with a special color variant of Shimhag's masterpiece rendition of Death herself.
The hand-signed option is in limited supply, so you must be swift.
For those that are unable to secure this extremely rare offering in time, do not fret.
By purchasing the entire set, a duplicated foil-stamped signature postcard will be sent as a bonus.
That is all from me, Death's maiden and dark fantasy enjoyer, Mori Calliope.
This year's goods are very different, but I wanted to pay tribute to a genre that I love so dearly...
...and has really made every day of my job so wonderful and happy.
I am so grateful to you guys for coming to enjoy my show as well.
Comment and let me know what your favorite part was.
Be sure to like the concert so others may be recommended it, and subscribe if you enjoy Mori Calliope.
With that, I bid thee farewell.
And Happy Birthday to me!!
Happy Birthday to me!!
6 birthdays high?! This time was even more
special than usual.
Much love to my guests, my Dead Beats, my band,
and everyone who wants to see me fly!
Let's have an even happier year together!!